Anandraj Elumalai

Software Developer

A Full Stack Developer with over 5 years of experience specializing in Software development in Banking and Finance (Cards and E-Payments) domain. Strong aspiration in designing and developing Cloud Native Applications. Interested in a challenging technical career with continuous learning and honing skills as passion.

anandrajpro@gmail.com

+919551553005

anandraj.dev

linkedin.com/in/anandrajelu in

github.com/anandrajelu (7)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer, Specialist

10/2019 - Present Product - Zelle

Fraud Machine Learning Model - FML Model

- Fraud Machine Learning Model is an advanced risk detection strategy for an electronic transaction. Every transaction will be scored based on the risk evaluation and various attributes of the transaction. The ML model provides a robust policy to handle fraudulent transactions using the most recent and current training data.
- Improved performance of the traversal logic by using Binary Tree implementation which mitigated the time complexity by
- Built Test model and production simulation models for the FML Model.

Fisery

Software Developer, Professional

10/2018 - 09/2019

AML-Anti Money Laundering Modularization

- Anti Money Laundering prevention is a compliance regulated by US government for all financial institutions handling electronic payments.
- Modularized the existing framework by using Spring Batch.
- Major contributor to the initiative and reduced number of production incidents reported due to the increased stability.

Wipro

Project Engineer

11/2015 - 10/2018

Client - Mastercard

Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS)

- PCI DSS is a set of security standards designed to ensure that all companies that accept, process, store or transmit credit card information maintain a secure environment. A new security module CSP - Cryptographic Security Protocol was created and restructured entire PIN processing system to adhere to the standards. Added flags and gradual routing of transactions to the new module.
- Major contributor to migration from current encryption standards by switching to CSP modules.
- Involved in code development and Code review process.
- Prepared Program Specifications and Test cases for all the enhancements and fixes for Point-toPoint testing.

EDUCATION

B.E. Computer Science and Engineering Veltech Hightech Engineering College

06/2011 - 01/2015

Avadi, Chennai

Final Year Project

 Created Enterprise Management Application as my Final year project using HTML, Java and MongoDB.

SKILLS

Java 1.8				•	•
Spring Boot	•	•	•	•	
Hibernate	•	•			•
Spring Batch					
Amazon Web Services					0
Microservices					0
Eureka Library	•	•	•	•	0
ReactJs	•	•	•	•	0
Relational Databases	•	•	•	•	0

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Developer Associate Amazon Web Services

02/2021 - 02/2024

No-SQL Databases

Score

973/1000

ORGANIZATIONS

Fiserv (10/2018 - Present)

Software Developer

Wipro (11/2015 - 10/2018)

Project Engineer

LANGUAGES

Tamil

Full Professional Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Hindi

Limited Working Proficiency

INTERESTS

Active player in LeetCode.com and Codechef.com which conducts monthly coding challenges.

Learning new

technologies/libraries/algorithms/architectures

Interested in calisthenics and fitness workouts.